Happy Diwali.
光明节快乐
Wish you all a very happy Diwali.
希望大家有一个非常快乐的光明节
You saw various kinds of dances.
你们看到这些不同种类的舞蹈
you must try to understand one thing from them
从而明白无论谁编写或谈论它们
Everyone spoke of one and the same thing.
都是说着同样的东西
The most important thing that everyone said
他们说最重要的是Paramatma
was 'God is one'.
是合一
'God is one'.
Paramatma却是唯一的
There is no dispute amongst them.
他们对此并无争议
They incarnate on Earth in order to destroy the evil
祂们来到世界是为摧毁邪恶
and to condemn the evil doers.
杀死坏人
That is happening everywhere.
这些事都在发生
I find everywhere
我看到每一处的坏人都被揭露
Now, it is your duty also
现在这也是你的责任
to identify them who are evil,
看到那些坏人
working against the will of God.
那些反对Paramatma的人
Those Who go to any extreme for the sake of money.
那些为钱可以干任何事的人
They  will all go to hell.
全都进地狱
We really do not know how many types of hells exist.
我不知道有多少个地狱
The environment or the place where you are sitting now
你们现在坐的地方
is far beyond those hells.
是远离地狱的
It has no connection with the hell at all.
与地狱毫不相干
But, in spite of your being at this place
若你留在这里
if you continue commiting sins and practice all sorts of wrong things,
却作出非宗教的行为 做些错误的事情
then  you could go to hell too.
那么你也会进地狱
There are various kinds of hell
有很多不同种类的地狱
and nice arrangements are there to go to those hells.
安排进地狱的过程是很美好的
Because,those who are supposed to go hell
要进地狱的人
can never even realize where are they going.
甚至不知道自己要往哪里去
While those who are saved,they go to the heaven.
留下来的人却会进天堂
So, sitting at earth level nobody can know
居住在这地球的人完全不知道
that "I'll have to go to hell',
自己会进地狱
or by commiting wrong things, 'I'll  go to hell'.
若我们做错事 也会进地狱
The meaning of 'Diwali' itself is :
Diwali的意思是
like the lamps lit outside,
像灯一样照亮外面
should be lit within you.
你内在也必须得到照亮 即开悟(enlightened)
You must also realize that you are
在这黑暗的世界
You are the lamps and you're the lights. You have to emit the light.
你是光 你是灯 你必须发光
But, if the same is not fully enlightened from within,
若你内在并未完全开悟
then how can you emit the light?
又怎能发光
You must also think  over it.
要明白这一点
That is why in the first place, the Sahaja Yogis
首先 霎哈嘉瑜伽士内在必须完全开悟
Possibly that was the purpose
可能这就是
for which we had to come to this world.
你们来到这个世界唯一的原因
Until Jesus Christ no one ever spoke on these subjects.
直至耶稣基督 连谈论这一点的人也没有
He incarnated at the Agnya Chakra level
基督在额轮降临
and showed the world that He did not have any ego within Him.
显示祂完全没有自我
He was the son of the God,
虽然祂是大能的神的儿子
yet He had no ego.
却没有自我
Those who came before Him
那些在祂之前来的人
spoke but very little.
只显现一点点
Christ came and wanted that our Agnya chakra should become all right.
基督只想我们的额轮能洁净
Incidentally that Agnya chakra catches too much in your Delhi.
在德里 额轮很阻塞
What could be the reason for it?
为甚么会这样
At the first place the English people came here to rule
英国人曾经在这里居住
and then Englishmen taught us arrogancy.
他们教我们要自我中心
They can easily be made out from your conversations.
你们言行举止完全能证明你们就是这样
I have seen those days also
我们曾经看过
when our country was dependent.
我们国家仍未独立的日子
But, you've come out of that dependency.
你们现在已经解放了
Now there is 'swatantrata'.
独立了
And what is 'swatantranta'  supposed to be?  Is to know the 'Swa'
甚么是Swatantra 知道Swa
('ownself') and whoever has known his 'Self',
即本性 拥有 Swa 即本性的知识的人
Knows the 'tantra' (system) of the 'Self'.
也拥有 tantra 的知识
Through Sahaja Yoga you have come to know about yourself.
藉由霎哈嘉瑜伽 你认识自己
And now you know that you are the 'tantra'.
你知道自己是 tantra 的工具
Therefore, you have to walk on the path of that 'tantra' of the 'self'.
你必须追随Swatantra的信道 即本性知识的信道
Lot of works have been done in Delhi, they are visible.
你可以看到德里有很多的建设
Works have also been done beyond Delhi.
德里外围也是
Now, the various problems in the people here are very well known to you.
你们都知道这里的人的问题
I need not tell you that.
不需要我告诉你
But , now that you have become 'swatantra' (independent),
现在你们已经独立
so you must be able to judge yourself whether you possess such problems within  or not.
你们必须看到 自己已经没有这些问题了
First of all the problem is
最先的问题是
that you have your own Agnya Chakra caught up.
你的额轮受感染
Jesus Christ passed away. He went to the cross,
虽然基督被钉十字架 被杀害
yet we did not learn anything from it.
我们却仍未从中学懂什么
On the contrary, wherever there are Christian countries,
相反 来自基督教国家的人
they possess tremendous ego.
却非常自我
They had their influence on us too.
我们受他们的影响
But, the worst part we find here is
在这里最差的要算是
that we donot know each other.
我们仍未互相确认
There is quarrel everywhere,
打斗争吵四处都是
fights everywhere.
争执持续着
There is no clarity in understanding amongst each other.
思维并不洁净
So the first thing is that our minds need to be cleansed.
我们首先要洁净自己的思维
Everything is possible in Sahaja Yoga.
藉由霎哈嘉瑜伽 什么都可能发生
People can attain any position from anywhere.
它可以把人带到那么高
It is not necessary for that reason to go and sit in the Himalayas .
我们不用跑到喜玛拉雅山 坐在上面
You can do it here in this city of Delhi itself.
在德里这个城市已经可以做到
But, if you look around,
若你环顾四周
you will find egoistical people.
你会看到四处都是自我中心的人
They have their Agnya chakra severely caught up.
他们的额轮阻塞得很厉害
So it is really very difficult.
所以处境是很困难
Now, god has given another new thing called 'cancer'.
现在神差遣了一件新东西来 就是癌症
If you have cancer and  your Agnya chakra is not set all right,
若你生癌 你的额轮便是不清洁
then it can never get cured.
你不能把癌治好
And there will be great trouble.
大麻烦会发生
That is why those who are suffering from cancer
所以任何生癌的人
should take to Sahaja Yoga
必须来霎哈嘉瑜伽
and the ego within you must be got rid of.
把自我清除
Because, wherever there is a government,
哪里有政府
ego comes into the people.
哪里的人便很自我
We have so many government servants here
现在这里有很多公务员
and they have a lot of ego within them.
他们的自我已经够大了
But, it is far more pronounced in the people
但外来的人的自我却比他们更大
to the ones here. And on top of it, they all drink alcohol.
除此之外 他们还喝酒
Just imagine they call themselves Christians
你只是在分析 他们称自己为基督徒
and they all drink alcohol.
却全都喝酒
Therfore by drinking alcohol, you are going against yourself only.
喝酒对你不利
You are blocking your own Agnya chakra.
你不服从自己的额轮
You are compltely ignoring it.
你不服从它
The person whose Agnya chakra is cleared out
额轮清洁的人不会喝酒
he can never drink alcohol.Never ever can have alcohol.
永远也不会
You find everywhere people drinking alcohol
无论你在哪里看到人喝酒
and neither do they have any means to control it.
他们都不能摆脱酒精
Because,whenever they try to overcome
当他们发现不能摆脱酒精
they start drinking even more.
便再次喝酒
So, any kind of'lat'[addiction] drags us to slavery
沉迷于任何事物令我们成为奴隶
... of any kind.
任何种类的沉迷也是
Now, these days here you will find addiction to chewing 'paan' (betel-leaves)
在这里 有人沉迷于paan
and on top of it, adds tobacco into it.
他们也把烟草加进去
Just imagine. God has created you with such great love
神创造我们拥有很多情感
in this country,
让我们在这个国家出生
so that you could become unique from the rest of the world.
我们因此变得独特
It can happen... and in fact the Indians are an example of that only.
他们可以是这样 印度人也是
But, now I find a they have developed few more obsessions,
但最近 我发现一些严重的疾病
.Like...  people here prefer to'eat money'rather than eating their 'meals'. (popular Indian proverb to denote practicing bribery).
他们以吃钱取代吃食物
Now, for example, the road by which I arrived here
我们来这里的道路
was not there earlier.
以前不是这样的
It shocked Me immensely to find that they have
我感到很伤痛的看到
constructed a new road recently. But, none can ever claim the same to be
这条路变成这样 没有人能说它是新建的
a newly constructed one. Only the Indians can do such works..
只有印度人才会做这种事
I have never seen such shameless people anywhere else in the world
我不曾在世界任何地方 看到这种毫无羞耻的人
who could do such work. After all these are not needed.
谁能做出种事 不需要这样做
Anytime, one who is bigger than the other with riches can do such work.
在这里 任何时候 任何有权势的人都可以做这种事
Therefore, today we need to acertain
首先 我们今天必须下定决心
in the first place that we must get our Agnya set right.
洁净自己的额轮
The greatest thing at the Agnya level is
额轮最严重的问题是
that we start thinking 'we are the best'
我们以为自己高高在上
and we believe that we can run the world,
我们开始视自己能统治全世界
we can reform the world.
纠正全世界
When you are not all right yourself,
若你自己也行为不当
Well, you must have seen a number of people
现在 你必定看到很多人
who respects and place you in high esteem
以为自己很伟大
and still do a lot of wrong things.
但却做了很多错事
In this country people are corrupt practising bribery [paise khatey hain].
这个国家的人收了很多钱
Tell Me how can god ever forgive us.
请告诉我 神怎会原谅我们
The worst of all sins are stealing and taking bribe.
最大的罪过(sin)是盗窃和贪污
The person who does these types of crimes,
犯这种罪的人
you may try anything on him ,even if the person himself may try to do anything, perform pujas,
无论他做什么 或许他作崇拜
prayers, chant mantras, recite text from holy scriptures, read namaz, pray in the name of Allah
念诵口诀 念诵名号 念诵Allah(神真伟大) 就算他做着各种这类的事情
they will be of no use to him.
仍然不能获益
Today is your new year.
所以 今天对你是新的一年
I wish you all the best.
我希望你们
And I want you to take a resolution
希望你们作出决定
that from today onwards we will not utter lies. Never, ever you will utter any lies.
从今天开始 不再说谎 永不说谎
I have been to places across the world and learnt that Indians are branded as great liars everywhere.
印度人以说谎闻名于世
I do not understand why such brandings have come upon our country
我不知道为什么会这样
that our people are liars.
我的国家被标签为不诚实
Where there have been so many great saints and prophets,
伟大的圣人 先知在这里出生
so many of them became Sufis,
人们怎能在一处很多苏非派(Sufis)
I wonder how people could speak up so much of lies there.
出生的地方说谎
So you've to promise today
所以今天 你必须承诺
that you will not tell lies
永不说谎
whatever may be the consequences.
无论这样会为你带来怎样的后果
For that, you need  courage.
你必须有勇气
But now that you are realized, what more of
因为你绝对不能说谎
courage do you require? for that matter You'll can never lie.
所以现在你知道自己需要有多大的勇气
Only when you become like that,
你只有是这样
people will start believing,
人们才会对你有信心
that these people are truthful.
你才是真正诚实的人
So the Sahaja Yogis have to be truthful.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士必须诚实
In whatever occupation
无论他是什么职业
may be in business or whatever,
无论他做什么
he may be an engineer constructing road or a doctor treating people.
他可能是建路的工程师 可能是医治人的医生
Nevertheless,
虽然如此
it can be hell for you if you still lie.
若你说谎 便会进地狱
Now you have transformed your own self,
因为你现在已经转化
you are realized now.
已经得到自觉
So, if the realized people ever lie,
有自觉的人说谎
then they can never achieve anything good out of it.
是绝对不能因说谎而得益
I feel very sad when I have to hear about our country from people outside
当我到海外 常常听到人说
that people here (in India) are very dishonest,liars
我们国家的人是骗子 说谎者 也很腐败
and make money (illegally).
我感到很悲痛
Today is your very auspicious day.
今天对你们来说是很吉祥的
Today you should all make sure
就让我们决定
that we shall never lie, whatever may come.
无论怎样 永不说谎
I am a woman Myself and that too of India.
我是女人 也是印度人
I have never lied.
我从不说谎
By lying, you'll only be at a loss.
说谎令你蒙受损失
By dishonesty, you'll only be at a loss.
你会为自己错误的行为而蒙受损失
In this manner even if you try to earn a bit more money or adopt other deceitful means
这样做 你可能赚得更多 骗取更多
you will never be able to go to heaven.
但你却不能进天堂
You can only go straight to hell.
你会进地狱
It is very important to know
有一点很重要 你们必须知道
there is a very bad reputation prevailing about us in other countries.
我们在全世界的声名很差
Why did this bad reputation happen?
为什么会这样
Because, we have such kind of people here.
因为我们都是这种人
If you come to know that someone is dishonest, then you should form a committee
当你知道某人好说谎 他组织了机构
for him and then question him, “Mister, what do you mean by all these”?
你便要问问
For example, supposing there is a road
例如若一条路建得不怎样好
then try to investigate how much has been spent behind it.
便会有人问多少钱花在建造这条路上
Then watch his actions to see what is he doing.
认可的成本是多少钱
Making money by such illegal means will
实际用了多少钱 他们从建路得的钱
be spent ultimately towards drinking alcohol only, which is our enemy.
只会花在喝酒上 喝酒是我们的敌人
Afterall,why do you want all these?
你们为什么这样做
You already have a very good living,
你们都是很富有的人
but there are many countries where people are poor,
我看到很多国家的人虽然穷
But I found them to be honest.
但却很诚实
So, honesty should be the first priority
诚实是你们最重要的品格
that needs to be ascertained today.
今天 我们作个决定
That we shall not commit dishonesty or
永远也不要不诚实
ever be in the company of dishonest people.
不要与不诚实的人为伍
Further, if anyone commits it, then we shall expose him.
任何人不诚实 我们都要揭露他
Now, people often grumbles,
现在就像这样
“Mother, similar things happen here also or
有人说 母亲 警队也是这样
similarly it prevails there also.”
其他部门亦是这样
But you are Sahaja Yogis.
你们是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Who are Sahaja Yogis,by no means are inferior to a policeman
并不比警察或其他有权力的人差
They possess great powers within them, but, all those powers come out of truth only.
你们都很有力量 所有力量都是真理
Truthfulness should be there.
必须有诚实
And I am very glad that
我很高兴
a lot of Sahaja Yogis are very truthful.Really Truthful.
很多霎哈嘉瑜伽士都很诚实
But, we require more Sahaja Yogis now
但我们仍需要有更多诚实的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Truthfulness is a very important aspect or else you could never
必须有诚实 否则你们的额轮便得不到洁净
get rid of your Agnya. The Agnya is the place where one has 'ego'.
自我是住在额轮
When ego develops in a person
当人变得自我
he commits any offence,
便会犯各种错误
any sin, criticizes, harms anyone, earns money illegally.
他好批评人 伤害人 变得堕落
They will all go to hell.
所有这类人都会进地狱
I would like to caution you, that
我想清楚的告诉你们
you should not earn money illegally.
不要堕落
It is not that you are dying
你不会死
what have you achieved by earning more
你必须要到达这种程度 赚更多的钱又怎样
What are you doing?
你可以怎样
You may have acquired a few lights (bulbs) more
你必须点亮多一些灯
and may have kept of a few more women around- And what more?
除此还能怎样
But, when you'll go to hell, what will be your condition then?
现在 当你进地狱 你将处于怎样的境况
I am speaking on this topic on the day of Diwali
在光明节的日子 我不停的谈论这些
because Diwali was celebrated
因为光明节是庆祝
when Sitaji had returned to reunite with Shri Rama.
悉旦与罗摩的重逢
Once our character is established,then  we can not remain slaves any more?
当我们拥抱贞操 便不再是奴隶了
We are our own slaves only, not of others even by any means.
我们是自己的奴隶而不是别人的奴隶
You are not to lie for any purpose.
无论什么原因 我们都不应说谎
I had been in Delhi for a very long period
我在德里已经住了很久
and I was surprised, how much the people lie here.
我因他们说了那么多谎言而感到很惊讶
My goodness – they aren't afraid at all .
他们完全不害怕说谎
Speaking lies so blatantly
他们可能因公开说谎而获益
even may help earn a few rupees extra.
可能赚更多的钱
but can never go to heaven.
但他们仍不知道自己将不能进天堂
I want the Sahaja Yogis to promise  today onwards,
希望霎哈嘉瑜伽士能答应我
'we neither shall ever lie nor ever support the liar .
不要说谎 也不要支持说谎的人
People comment about our country that we are very dishonest.
人们说我们的国家很腐败
I have travelled into far remote places
是 我曾经到过很远的地方
and I found the people of Russia are  very good.
我看到俄国人是最好的
They are already half-Sahaja Yogis
他们有一半像霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and there are so many  Sahaja Yogis too.
很多霎哈嘉瑜伽士在哪里
I was not able to go to Russia this year.
今年我将不能去俄国
I shall definitely visit next year.
明年我一定会去
However, this  makes it clear that
这样是显示
we can not handle democracy.
我们不能好好的实行民主
We too should have been communist.
我们必须也是共产主义
Neither there is any stealing,trickery nor any lies spoken in those places
在哪里 没有抢劫 没有说谎
and they all love each other very much.
每个人都相亲相爱
There is great respect for Me too.
他们对我很尊重
But, it needs to be understood where are we  leading to after all. (       ^-where are we heading towards?)
我们必须明白自己该往何处去
Just for the sake of earning a few more (rupees), where are we heading?
为着赚更多的钱 我们可以到怎样的程度
What are we going to achieve?
我们可以得到什么
Therefore, to begin with you must be honest.
诚实是我们内在最重要的品格
Your dishonesty  will cause trouble  to your own people.
你的不诚实会为你的人民带来问题
People blame India, claiming that people of this place are very  dishonest.
人们说印度人是不诚实的
I am ashamed to hear all this.
我听到这些话会感到羞愧
You have had so many great saints
那么多圣人在这里出生
so many great souls from here
有多少先知曾经到过这里
and here the people are frauds
但这地方的人却是贼
they cheat a lot and also criticize .
他们偷窃 他们批评
So, in the beginning itself your Agnya is scared.
一开始你的额轮便因为所有这些而受惊
They will become very wealthy.
他们想赚大钱
But, in the end you find that Mr. wealthy is going to hell.
最后 所有这些有钱人都会进地狱
Today, I want to tell you the
在这光明节 我想告诉你
meaning of Diwali is that-
光明节的意思是
hell is dark and you have become the light.
地狱充满黑暗
It is expected of you that you must fight wherever there is darkness
你们全都已经开悟 我期望你们能对抗黑暗
and make it known publicly that it is wrong.
让他们知道自己的行为是错误的
With this our country is going to improve.
若大家都这样做 我们的国家便会得到改善
This is yet another job that you have to do.
你们必须都这样做
We are performing puja rituals already.
在作崇拜和所有的仪式时
But,the innate power that is within us is the one
我们内在的shakti(神圣的力量)
which stands opposed to  all that is untrue.
在对抗一切不诚实
Many people are obsessed with earning illegal money and do not know
很多人不知道赚钱是一种病态
that directly they will go to hell.
他们会直接进地狱
I am telling you all these
我告诉你们这些
since no one ever spoke about it before.
是因为没有人曾告诉你们
On this day of Diwali let us say
在光明节 我告诉你
that we will celebrate the joy
我们会把灯点亮 庆祝在我们内心的喜乐
In that light we will be able recognize
因此我们能看到
who is in what state and who are cheating.
自己是什么类型的人 是否一个窃贼
Now,I notice another kind of fight.
现在也一样 我看到人们争吵
Fights between the Hindus and Muslims are  over,
印度教徒与穆斯林的争吵已经结束
now others have picked up fighting.
但与别人的争吵却刚开始
It means we are also very quarrelsome.
这是第二件事 就是我们也喜欢争吵
At least in the other countries
至少在其他国家
one does not find religions of so many countries in one place.
没有我们那么多宗教
But, at the slightest opportunity we pick up  fights here.
所以当我们一有机会 便开始争吵
Fighting becomes the priority.
争吵有优先权
Fights between husband and wife, then within their children
丈夫与妻子争吵 跟着是他们的孩子
and also amongst them who are in contact with each other.
任何人与他们一起 他们也与他们争吵
What is Sahaja Yoga?
什么是霎哈嘉瑜伽
Sahaja Yoga is love. Love.
霎哈嘉瑜伽是爱 只是爱
Awaken that power of love that is within you.
它把我们内在的爱唤醒
Today is supposed to be a very auspicious day.
今天是非常吉祥的日子
We have to light the lamps in our hearts and make it certain by all means
我们要把内心的灯点亮 请你们作出承诺
that, even if we have to die, we won’t tell lies.
你们或许会死但却不能说谎
We already have such people with us.
这里有很多伟大的人
But, our reputation across the world is so much damaged claiming
但在全世界 印度人的声誉
that Indians have become dishonest.
仍然是被视为不老实
Well, I have never come across one atleast,
虽然我不曾见过任何一个这样的人
but when discussed, I feel very sad.
但当我听到这种话 我感到很伤心
A holy place like India
印度是神圣的地方
where great saints had taken their birth
很多伟大的圣人在这里出生
unlike any other place. Sufis were also born here.
这种事并没有在世界其他地方发生 苏非派在这里出生
all those who became great had been from India only.
他们变得很伟大 全都在印度出生
No other countries ever had so many great souls.
很多伟大的圣人不在世界其他地方出生
A few may have been there,
他们有些人必须在这里出生
but we have had several great souls here.
在印度出生的 都是非常伟大的圣人
But, later even after ignoring whatever they might have taught us,
但之后 他们的教诲却被人放弃
we became branded thieves.
我们变成声名狼藉的贼
So whoever cheats people they can never ascend to heaven.
任何犯盗窃的人 永远不能进天堂
Compaired to the lifespan spent here,
你会花比在这里
one has to spend a lifespans that is thousand times more in hell.
多千倍的时间留在地狱
The reason I am speaking about hell
今天我在谈论地狱
on this day is only because hell means the darkness
因为地狱代表黑暗
and that is the hell that we witness.
我们看到四处都是黑暗 那是地狱
Now your lamps are lit. In that light, you must
现在你的灯已经被点亮 尝试看看谁在地狱
You should support the government.
你要揭露不诚实以支持政府
Extend help to identify ,who are dishonest. You may be in a junior or a senior
无论你的职位是低是高
position, but you must speak it out
也要揭露那些窃贼
Expose those who are liars.
那些贪污的人
Now you have the powers with you – for  what purpose? You are awakened,
现在你已拥有力量 为什么你要拥有力量 你已经被唤醒
for what purpose? You are enlightened.
为什么要唤醒你 你已经开悟了
In  that light, you must see yourself.
在这光中 你看清自己
In darkness we acheive nothing, but
在黑暗中 你什么也看不到
watch in your own light to realize what you are.
但在光中 你看到你是谁
Also by lying  what are you going to achieve?
看到说谎可以为你带来什么
I am a housewife.I have never lied. Never ever. Neither can ever.
我们是有家庭的人 我们永不说谎 永不 我们甚至不能说谎
The moment you are compelled to lie,
在任何可能要说谎的情况下
you have the powers within, you are all lamps.
不要忘记你拥有力量 你就是光
You just see them in this darkness.
你要明白 你就是黑暗中的光
and the lamps are supposed to give light.
要令光继续燃烧
We have to wipe out this darkness.
我们必须结束这黑暗
There is a bad reputation about us from far across.
不诚实为我们带来坏名声
While the fact is , nowhere else you will ever find people like that of our country.
没有任何国家比我们的国家伟大
It gives great pain when I learn
知道外面的人误解我们是很悲哀的
God knows what does one achieve by dishonesty?
我也不知道不诚实为这些人带来什么
But whatever may be the outcome, it is horrible.
他们取得的都是很可怕
No one will be spared.
没有人会被宽恕
Whoever has become dishonest will be caught.
任何人不诚实都会被揭发
There are all arrangements for that.
这是已有安排的
You have got your Realization because you are not dishonest.
你们得到自觉是因为没有不诚实
You love truth and respect the truth.
你们爱诚实 尊重诚实
I want that you should stand on truth.
我希望你们象征真理
Now for example,people throw garbage into the river Yamuna.It is stupidity.
那些向Jamunaji(河流) 乱抛东西的人是蠢人
Yamunaji itself descends directly to hell,
Jamunaji是直接通往地狱的
but you will be saved from that hell since
你可以从地狱中被拯救
you are realized souls.
你是已得自觉的灵
One who has the light generally do not fall.
已经开悟的人永不倒下
But, if you sincerly want to establish Sahaja Yoga fully within yourself,
若你真的想内在完全建立霎哈嘉瑜伽
then in the beginning, you have to swear that you
必须首先决定 无论怎样
will never commit dishonesty of any kind.
也不要不诚实
It seems earning money has become the only means of business left out in this world.
赚钱是这个世界唯一的事情
What does one get out of it?
若是这样 什么会发生
Nobody even remembers them.
没有人会记得他们
If you love your country, then at first you must establish the truth
若你爱你的国家 你必须诚实
or else who can trust the liar?
否则 有谁会相信说谎的人的爱
It is a big hurdle for you
对你来说
because you always have a feeling that when my neighbour is like this
看到你的邻居是这类人是很不幸的
then why  I too don't become like that?
你想你自己也会变成这样
But,  why don’t you think instead when I can belike this,
相反 你为什么不想想 我们是这样
then why not transform my neighbour likewise?
我的邻居为什么不能像我们
First of all, today you must promise that we shall neither
首先 你必须承诺 永远不要不诚实
commit any dishonesty nor support any dishonest person.
也不要支持不诚实的人
Falsehood in our country, not sure why, but
我还未知道说谎者的兴起
seems like a curse on us.
是否是我们国家的咀咒
There are several people who would not be  satisfied until they utter
有很多人从早到晚至少说十个大话
at least ten lies from morning until evening.
对他们这还不足够
Now your poverty is finished. Everything is quite all right.
现在你已经脱离贫穷 各样事情都很美好
All food and stuff are available.
得到温饱
None of you are beggars, yet why do you lie?
不再是乞丐 为什么还要说谎
So let this be the resolution of the day
所以在今天 要作出承诺
that you will not lie any more and, if anyone is a liar then
我们不要说谎 任何说谎的人
we shall not join hands to rejoice with that person.
我们都不支持
We will have no relationship with him.
不与他们有任何连系
There  is plenty of joy in it.
这样我们便会平和快乐
Because, do you know that a liar will go to hell
你知道说谎的人会进地狱
and you too will follow him from behind.
若你支持他们 你也会随他们进地狱
God has given you Realization.
神给你自觉
You have the light within and in that light you should identify the
你内在已经开悟 看 在这光中
other like-minded people and then must
若要其他人像你
decide that we will not lie whatever may come,
你必须承诺 永不说谎
even if we are beheaded.
就算为此要切下你们的头 什么也可以
In these  matters I know the Indians are very good.
这方面 印度人是比较好
But when I hear certain comments about them outside
我知道 当我在外面听到有关他们的话
then  I feel very sad.
我感到非常伤心
For example, the road that is constructed,
这条路是怎样建造的
does it resemble a road by any means?
它是路吗
I felt if I was travelling in the jungles.
我感到我们像走过森林
Whenever you come across such a thing, you have
我们拥有有关机构
an organization; you must collectively inquire as to
当你看到这种事情 你可以质问
who were responsible for the construction? Why it had to be constructed that way?
谁建造这种路 他为什么这样建路
Who had consumed the money? All the Sahaja Yogis should get united
谁侵吞了建路的钱 霎哈嘉瑜伽士必须团结
and try focussing your attention in that  direction to drive out the bhoots
把这亡灵从我们的国家赶走
out which have crept into India. Wherever you go,you will hear people commenting:
无论我们走到哪里 人们都会说
“Brothers, don’t believe in the Indians." What a shame.
不要相信印度人 这是何等羞耻
The irony is: in who one should
我们印度人 本应是最值得信任的人
trust the most are we Indians only. Nevertheless, we had so many of them
我们拥有
who were great leaders, great people and great souls.
伟大的领导人 伟大的圣人 伟大的灵
But we have completely ignored them and their great fame of past.
我们并没有想到他们的名声 他们的声誉
How much amount of respect people had for them and also they have for you too – I know that.
多少人尊重他们 他们也尊重你
But you should never extend company or support to the cheats.
不要支持窃贼
The moment you realize that a certain person is a cheat,
若你知道某人是贼
then even avoid having meals at his home.
不要到他的地方吃喝
It will become very difficult for the cheats to survive.
这样会令贼感到为难
I am telling you that
我告诉你
you  all are the police force of God.
你是上天的警察 要留意你遇到的贼
Keep track of all those cheats that you come across.
要谆谆善诱
Try to instill courage in your children.
这份勇气也要教导给你的孩子
If one is doing something wrong or lying, identify them.
尝试找出犯错和说谎的人
This country has received blessings alongwith many other saints.
我们的国家已经被很多圣人唤醒
and you all are saints.
你们全都是圣人
There is no need for you to lie.
没有需要说谎
Well, what's going to happen if you have one time meal only?
若你只能一天进食一次 什么会发生
Nobody dies if one doesnot have a meal.
没有人会因此而死亡
We do have food
人是需要饮食
but they prefer drink alcohol.
除此之外 我们还想喝酒
By drinking alcohol, we take a step further towards our own destruction.
第二是喝酒令我们寸步难行
If there is alcohol
相反 酒精破坏我们
we can never be all right.
酗酒令我们活得不好
Now for example, in America,
就如在美国
they always come up with newer subjects,
他们有新的问题
Like the moment their children turns sixteen
孩子到十六岁
they become worthless. Does this mean that  they are all like servants?
必须自己赚钱 这代表所有人都是仆人
When they work or wash cars they are paid for it.
无论他们为你做什么 都要给钱他们 如洗车等
And what they claim as they attain the age of sixteen?
在十六岁 他们会说
“Well, now that we have turned sixteen and so it is the time to go out for a living.”
先生 你已经十六岁了 现在要走出家门
I have seen this happening with the
我在每一处都看到
poor children of sixteen everywhere,
这些只有十六岁的可怜孩子
whereas we (in India) think, “He is just turning sixteen,
我想 他只是刚满十六岁
where will he go or What should he study?”
他可以往哪里去 怎样受教育
But,(in America) since he has turned sixteen years of age,
他现在十六岁了 被赶出家门
he is driven out of the home both by his mother and father.
他的父母把他赶出家门
Just keep on watching for how long is this going to last with the Americans?
美国人要持续这样做多久 你只看看
They are in the state of destruction.
他们正在崩溃
Nobody becomes great by buying one or two airplanes.
只购买一两只飞机 不会令人变得伟大
Where do you think you are? How far are your limitations?
你在哪里 你有什么能力
India is such a country that it can save the entire world
印度这个国家可以服务全世界
– the entire world. But there should be truthfulness in it.
全世界
It is very essential to imbibe the truthfulness. Truthfulness in each and every matter.
为此 必须有诚实
I can’t understand, What is the need for nurturing falsehood?
有什么需要虚假 我就是不明白
people who are rich should realize in the begining itself that they are already rich.
大部分富人必须首先知道自己是富有的
So it is better for them to sit back quietly and stop planning to earn anymore.
现在安静坐下 不要想多赚钱
I am yet to see Who is happy
我不曾见过有人 因为多赚钱而变得更快乐
You are a Sahaja Yogi and you have the light within you.
你们是霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你们内在有光
In the light you lead other and the path is of truth.
在这光中 你看到你的道路 你的道路是真理
May you be a Muslim, a Hindu or a Christian. It makes no difference.
你可能是穆斯林 可能是印度教徒 可能是基督教徒 全都没有分别
You all are humans. And if honesty is missing in a person,
你们全是人类 若人类没有诚实
then he is dishonest. No one will recognize him.
他们就是不诚实 没有人会认出他
We have to spend lifespan even beyond this also. How will that be?
我们拥有超越这个的生命 怎会这样
Through honesty there can be several benefits.
诚实有很多益处
The greatest of all is that
最重要的是
you have the blessings of God on you.
你拥有与神同在的福气
Blessings come in such a manner that
当你知道你拥有神的什么祝福
you will be astonished to know
你会感到很惊讶
that everything are effortlessly accomplished on its own.
不用花任何力气 你的所有事情都井然有序
But now in India, everyone runs after money
但现在在印度 人们无论拥有什么 他们或许拥有这些
whether they have or donot have.
或许没有这些 全都只追逐金钱
Yet, there are many poor around.
穷人仍然很多
That is why today Diwali should be for them also.
所以今天的光明节 也要为他们庆祝
They too should be happy.
他们也应该快乐
We are citizens of that country.
我们住在同一个国家
But we deceive ourselves only. We pose to be  very clever.
却欺骗自己
By this, ego develops within us. And when ego is developed,
因为我们聪明 内在变得自我 变得自我
nobody can save by any means.
没有人能拯救你
With ego, you will develop cancer.
自我令你生癌
Therefore you will not be able to save yourself
你救不了自己
if you develop cancer. You cannot save yourself.
若你有癌症 你便救不了自己
I cannot save you. I am telling you the truth.
我也救不了你 我告诉你的都是事实
So, first of all , you should burn the ego in fire that you possess within .
首先用火把你的自我烧掉
If you have ego then you must be ashamed of it.
若你有自我 你应该感到羞耻
“Ego for what"?
为什么会有自我
It is prevelent for everything in our country .
在我们的国家 可以因为各种原因
Someone passes a Bachelor degree examination,  he develops ego.
有人得了学位 便有自我
Achieving someother  qualification higher than that gives him double ego.
若他得了比学位更多的 他便拥有双倍的自我
One achieves something,
某人有任何成就
becomes an engineer or a doctor,
例如他成为工程师或医生
he develops ego.
他便变得自我
Thus, when this Agnya chakra gets caught,
当他的额轮受感染
where does it ultimately lead you to? To hell.
它可以带你到哪里 进地狱
And hell is a very horrible place.
地狱是一处可怕的地方
God has blessed you with intelligence
神赐予你们聪明才智
and now you have got your Realization.
你们现在都得到自觉
Still if you want to go to the hell, you can go.
虽然如此 若你仍想进地狱 也可以
Until this day nobody spoke about it or told you.
没有人向你们说及这些
Today is the day that is considered auspicious
今天是吉祥的日子
because several good things happened.
因为很多事情在今天发生
During the period of Ramachandraji, Sitaji returned home.
悉旦在“Ramchandraji”这段时间回来
During Krishna’s times and several other occasion that were marked by great events
任何伟大的行为也在 Krishnaji
were all worked out by the realized souls.
这段时间由已得自觉的灵完成
That is why, in the first place, you must take a vow today that
所以我们首先决定 与此同时
“We will not commit any dishonesty for sure
不要有任何不诚实的行为
and if anyone does, then we shall ensure
若任何人做出不诚实的行为
that he is caught.”
便要揭露他
But I notice that in this country the blacks are at war with the whites
我看到在这个国家 白人与黑人争吵
any one picking up fight with the other.
一些人与另一些人争吵
They want to divide India into fragments.
他们想印度分裂
It is not going to benefit anyway. But how is it going to benefit?
这对大家绝对没有任何益处 当你是诚实的 拥有好的品格 这又怎会是对你有利呢
Whatever you have learnt from the English,
无论我们从英国人学懂什么
there was nothing worth learning from them.
没有什么是值得向他们学习
They are all in a bad state these days.
他们现在的状况很差
But we have to save our own country
我们现在要拯救自己的国家
and also to save the entire world. It is a great responsibility.
拯救全世界 这是一个很重要的责任
You have been realized and the light has come within you.
你已经有自觉 已经开悟了
Yet, you want to jump into the ditch,what can anyone do?
若你仍想跌进沟渠里 别人又可以怎样
Everyone should join together to make an effort.
每个人必须走在一起 去尝试
I want the Sahaja Yogis should constitute a committee.
我想霎哈嘉瑜伽士组成一个委员会
In case you come across any cheating,
若你们发现任何偷窃的行为
you should report it to the committee.
必须告诉委员会
Then let us see what the committee does.
再看看委员会怎样做
In this way, you'll earn a good name.
这样你便会有好名声
In this way, you will be elevated to higher positions.
会到达高位
So, in the first place neither you be a dishonest yourself
所以首先你们不应不诚实
nor let any other be.
也不应让别人不诚实
This is very important for you have
这是非常重要的
great blemish on your country.
你的国家已经被玷污了
There is adulteration in the edible oil,
油已经掺了杂质
adulteration in the ghee.
酥油也掺了假货
Everywhere  people make a mockery at us.
无论在哪里 人们都在笑我们
No one has faith in us.
没有人相信
In fact, the best of the people are in India.
实际上最好的人是在印度
Nowhere you find so many people
在这里得到自觉的人
who have had their realization.
比世界任何地方的多
They have not earned any sort of punyas(virtues/spiritual merits).
他们没有赚到任何美德
Therefore, it is nobler to earn punyas than to earn money.
赚取美德比赚取金钱好
Look at those people who are very poor.
看看那些非常贫穷的人
So today is a very auspicious day and also a day of joy.
今天是非常吉祥的日子 也是非常喜乐的日子
Joy for what? Because on this day we have been blessed
为什么喜乐 因为今天我们拥有天堂
with heaven and we desire to be in heaven only.
我们只想留在天堂
But cowards can never make it to heaven.
胆小的人不能进天堂
There is no need to be afraid.
不需要害怕
Well, what diaster is going to come even if you earn
若你拥有多一两个卢比
a few paise(Indian currency coin) less or more?
灾难会否临在你身上
All of you have become rich. I can see that is quite visible and
全部人都变得富有 我曾经看到这样
I have been coming here(Delhi) for the past 17 or 18 years now.
我在过往十七八年都有来这里
All of you have become richer than before.
你们都变得比过往富有
Conditions have improved now compared to earlier.
环境也比过往好
But, from morning until evening there is
但却从早到晚 不停的
dishonesty, dishonesty and dishonesty.
不诚实 不诚实 不诚实
So, the path is now laid down before you. therefore,just promise today
路已经建好 今天只要作出承诺
that we shall not commit any dishonesty and, if anyone is found doing
我们不会不诚实 任何人不诚实
then we shall collectively oppose him.
我们都会一起对抗他
Why did Sahaja Yoga
为什么给你霎哈嘉瑜伽
give you Realization?
给你自觉
It is because you will emit light.
因为这样才可以传播光
If you do not posses light within, then how can you emit light outside?
若你内在没有光 你又怎可以外在的传播光
In that light try to see for yourself whether you are helping the dishonest?
在这光中 你是否看到你在帮助不诚实的人
Nothing happens if you earn a little less or more.
无论赚多赚少 也不会有任何事情发生
If you are honest, then God helps you.
若你诚实 神会帮助你
Now , you see for yourself , I never take money from anyone.It is true.
为什么死在我们国家的人 比死在其他国家的多
But, I wrote a book
很多人
and received lots of money from it.
原因是他们都要进地狱
I shall neither allow anyone to take anything.
所以你要知道
Why do so many people die in our country
若不诚实
compared to anywhere else?
你已经踏进地狱的第一步
The reason is because people want to go to hell.
说谎这第二步已经不再需要了
So, you should know this, that if you commit dishonesty,
你说事实
then your first step have already been established in hell
说真话的人是独一无二的
and secondly you don’t need to utter lies at all.
若他是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
You must speak the truth.
那就更好
The man who speaks the truth becomes a unique person.
就像人记得苏非派
If he practises Sahaja Yoga, then it can be remarkable.
你同样会被人记得
As you are remembering the Sufis today,
你什么也不需要做
similarly people will remember you then.
只要抓住不诚实人
You don’t need to do anything
这是很需要的
only expose those who are dishonest.
这里的人
It is important.
为阻止人
Here the people are querreling...
把东西抛进Jamunaji而抗争
"Don't throw garbage into the Yamunaji and
必须告诉他们
don’t throw that". Now, do this also needs to be told.
我曾经到过很多国家
I have been to so many countries.
没有人
Nowhere the waste is disposed into any river.
会把垃圾抛进河里
Then why are you so lazy? There are so many facilities made available.
你们为什么那么懒惰 这里有很多设施
You can hand it over to the municipality or dispose it elsewhere.
你可以把垃圾交给市政府 或把它扔弃在某处
But if you are accumulating the waste yourself,
若你自己扔弃垃圾
then what can you do?
别人又可以怎样做
All of you should think in your mind and decide today.
今天 你们全部人心里要作决定
It is a very good day today. It is a good day.
今天是非常吉祥的日子
That neither  shall we ever commit any dishonesty nor acknowledge the dishonest.
我们不作任何不诚实的行为 不相信任何不诚实
I have seen such people
我见过有人不是不诚实
who neither had been dishonest nor ever visited the house
也不到不诚实的人的家
of any dishonest person. They never kept any connection with them.
他们与这些人毫无关连
because they not only harmed themselves
因为他们关注的不单是自己的福祉
but had also been harmful for the nation..
还是整个国家的福祉
Now you are a Sahaja Yogi.
你是霎哈嘉瑜伽士
You should promise that
你需要作出承诺
we shall never commit any dishonesty.
不要做任何不诚实的事
And if some one happens to be dishonest
只要认出任何不诚实的人
For that you need not think "why to beat him, there is government to look after".
便告诉你内在的灵
It doesn't matter.
他是不诚实的
and tell it to your inner Sprit that he is dishonest.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士
And for the Sahaja Yogis – even if 12 Sahaja Yogis can unite and collectively
就算只有十二位走在一起
identify that this particular person is dishonest,
若你们知道他是不诚实的
then God is with you.
上天会支持你
Merely by a handful of rich people the welfare of  the country cannot improve.
这个国家不会因为少数的富人而得益
But with honest people, certainly it can.
却肯定能从老实的人而得益
So, the greatest blemish on us is
我们最大的污名是不诚实的
And those who are Sahaja Yogis can never be dishonest by any means.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士永远也不要不诚实
This is My belief.
我们必须团结
Leave aside all differences.
停下争吵
We are all honest people, India’s reputation is greatly tarnished.
承担起我们是诚实的人 印度的形象已经受到玷污
That is why take a vow from today
所以今天请你们立誓
that we shall not commit any dishonesty and if there are
从现在开始 不要不诚实
any other dishonest person, we shall collectively chase after him.
任何不诚实的人 我们都要训斥他
He is sure to experience a sleepless night the next day itself.
明天他便会不能安睡
Nevertheless, it has gone too far.
虽然这种事越来越多
Now I've to tell you that I am astonished.
我对不诚实已经到达这程度感到很震惊
There is dishonesty in everything – dishonesty in everything.
任何事情都不诚实
Where ever you notice any dishonesty,
之前他们通常排斥所有的小事
In the earlier days people used to outcast others on petty matters.
把自己与小事分开
But, our country had remained so honest and
我们的国家曾是那么诚实
had such great qualities.Why have we forgotten them?
拥有很好的品格 我们是否已经忘记了这些品格
Where have they all gone?
它们去了哪里
I find there is dishonesty everywhere. Dishonesty at every step.
我可以看到四处都是不诚实 每一步都是不诚实
You must teach the children here that they should not become dishonest.
我们必须教导孩子不要不诚实
In case they are dying of starvation
对 就算他们要饿死 也会有安排
then  arrangements could be made suitably,
只要他是诚实的
But if honesty is not there,leave alone God,
若你不诚实 什么人也帮不了你
no one is going to help you. All kinds of diseases will come upon you.
就算神也不能 他会染上各种疾病
Coincidently, our country is full of such remarkable traditions, they are countless...
我们国家有很多这种传统
For example, they will drink alcohol,liquor just imagine!
他们喝酒 请告诉我
Were you born to become a stupid?
你来这里是否要变成蠢人
Stop being friendly to the person, who does it. Don’t support him.
不要成为这种人的朋友 不要帮助他们
I have noticed that people who
我看到人们到喝酒的人的家
drink alcohol,people visit their houses and
跟着他们也开始喝酒
they also join in drinking alcohol. But if you come to know
当你知道有人是这种品格
or a particular person is dishonest, then stop having meals in his house.
当你知道他是不诚实 不要再在他的地方吃喝
You should not have any concern (for them).
你与他毫不相干
We have to work for the betterment of our country
因为神赐予我们光
because god has given us the light.You must judge in that light.
我们要为我们国家的福祉而工作
His powers are tremendous.
在这光中 祂的力量是很巨大的
If you are able to realize that those who had been dishonest
若你决定这样
to the nation will be taken care of by God.That will work out everything. It is enough.
神便会照顾那些对国家不诚实的人 这样已经足够了
But, you seem to have turn deaf and refuse to understand.
但你却变成聋子 你就是不能理解
Such people neither can ever do good
这种人永远也不会有好的行为
nor can ever deliver.
他也不会有任何付出
I don’t understand how do those shameless people exist? I really donot know.
我就是不明白 他们怎能活得这样毫无羞耻
For that reason, today's message for you is
这就是为什么今天的信息是
that you must vow on this day onwards
我们必须立誓
that we shall never ever commit any dishonesty
无论如何 也不要不诚实
and if someone is dishonest, then we shall not support him.
任何人不诚实 我们都不支持他
That is enough.
这就已经足够了
Many more realized souls will come to our country.
有更多已得自觉的灵会来到我们的国家
But, who would like to be born in such a dishonest country like this?
但谁又会想来这个不诚实的国家
The only message for you today is that you have the light within
今天唯一的信息是你已拥有光
and you have carry forward your mission in that light
若你走在光中
that is going to provide you the strength.
便会给你力量
Whatever you wish to do, you are welcome.
你可以做你想做的事情
Look, we have achieved our 'swatantrata'.
看 我们已经成就了 swatantra
'Swa'-'tantra'...try to know the 'swa'(ownSelf).
swatantra 是令我们明白自己的基制
Now, I want that many children to be born. They should be realized.
我希望更多有自觉的孩子出生
That is why you must learn in the begining.....
所以你们要认识
Today is a great day.
今天是伟大的日子
You must promise today that neither will we commit any dishonesty nor be involved with the dishonest persons.
今天你要立誓 不要不诚实 亦不要支持不诚实的人
or be afraid of them.
不要被他们吓倒
God is never with them. God is with you.
神从未与他们同在 神是与你同在
If you are good, then God is with you.
若你是好的 神便会与你一起
Everyone of you were born in this land of India, it indeed wasn't for the sake of
所有人 都不是为了战争
fighting amongst each other to die.
跟着死去而在印度这伟大的土地出生
Ignorant fools, we fight each other and then die.
伟大的蠢人 我们作战 然后死去
There is no use in fighting, you should tell this to people.
战争是一无是处 告诉他们
“Well, what are you fighting for ?
啊 你们为什么争吵
What do you want? Why? After all, what do you want?
你想要什么 无论如何
There is enough to eat and drink. What more do you want?”
你吃好喝好 你还想要什么
But, nowadays the demands are like ,
现在最流行的是我们想要这种衣服
“I need that dress, I want such kind of house
想要这种类型的房子
and not this type.”
我们并没有这些
And with all those, let's go to hell.
拥有这些只会令我们进地狱
At this moment...(Inturrupted by Sir CP and speaking to Sir CP)
这些日子
Like those who had become Sufis, you are all Sufis too
很多稣非派 与他们一样 你也是稣非派
because you have been cleansed.
因为你们都已经洁净
Now all of you should write poems – on honesty.
你们现在编写诚实的诗歌
This element of dishonesty needs to go in the first place
这种不诚实必须摆脱 这是第一件事
and secondly, there are many issues that need to be taken care of.
第二是很多事情必须得到纠正
But first of all, never commit dishonesty.
但看看 首先不要跟随不诚实
No one is that poor in India
没有人在印度是穷得要依靠不诚实
What I am saying is, there is a blemish on our country and it needs to be wiped out.
我在说我们的国家已经被玷污 这必须清除
And you are Sahaja Yogis. You can do it.
你们都是霎哈嘉瑜伽士 你们都能做到
You have the light with you. With it
你拥有光 藉由这光
you can spread the light everywhere.
你可以把光传播到每一处
You must encourage everyone to show the  right things.
给予所有人勇气 那么事情便会妥当
Those young amongst you, who are friends
特别是那些年青的 那些朋友
should think what honestful work they can undertake.
必须想想有什么诚实的行为你可以做
Now a campaign is initiated  to prohibit dumping anything into River Yamunaj.
现在他们开始不再把垃圾抛进Jamunaji
That is all right, but it is not as important.
这样做没有不妥 但并不怎样重要
More important aspect is losing one's honesty.
重要的是要抛弃不诚实
That is why this day is considered auspicious everywhere.
这就是为什么今天
Lamps are lit at all the places.
每一处都被视为吉祥
Everything is done and if we can’t do this bit,
各处都点亮着灯 虽然如此 若你这样也做不到
then there is no use being a sahaj yogi.
霎哈嘉瑜伽有什么好处呢
We have the  largest collectivity of Sahaja Yogis in India – the largest collectivity.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士最多的地方是印度
Next to it is in Russia.
跟着是俄罗斯
Now, the Russians are very humble.
现在俄罗斯人都很有礼貌
they dont steal or cheat
他们不会打劫
I really don’t understand how?
我不知道为什么
Maybe if communism comes here,probably
或许若共产主义来到印度
we too would become like them.
我们也会变得像他们一样
But it does not make very big sense.
这不是一件很伟大的事
It is not good to impose compulsion to achieve anything..
任何事强迫去做都不好
Let us impose strictness on ourselves.
我们要决定自己必须变得有力量
Decide it for good. Take up the resolution today only.
今天你要作决定
Today is a very good day to start,
今天是非常吉祥的日子
that neither shall we commit any dishonesty nor let others commit it.
我们不要不诚实 也不要让别人不诚实
Your country will become very prosperous.
这样你的国家便会大大的昌盛
And after all what is any other country? I have seen all of them.
我曾经见过其他国家是怎么样 他们的人是怎么样
All are useless people.
全是一无是处的人
But,people of our country still have a lot of dharma(righteousness) in them.
我们国家的人仍然喜好虔敬
The dharma in our country has been destroyed
若这些不诚实的人变得有力量
since the dishonest became all the very powerful.
我们国家的虔敬便会消失
So the only  message today is
所以唯一的信息是
that neither we shall ever commit dishonesty nor allow anyothers to commit.
我们不要不诚实 也不要容许别人不诚实
But the people here are very tolerant in this matter.
在这里的人却对这很容忍
They tolerate. This is the greatest mistake.
他们容忍 这是他们犯最大的错误
When you have got the light, then why do you fear?
当你有光 为什么还要害怕
What is the reason for you to be afraid?
有什么需要害怕
That is why I am requesting you today to do everything with courage.
这就是我为什么今天请求你们 要有勇气
And now you have got a kind of swatantrata (freedom).
现在一种解放已经成就到 你会到达 swatantra
You will attain (knowledge) the tantra (the system) of the swa (Self).
tantra(机制)的 swa(自己)
You have already attained it,
你已经到达了
but try to make use of it.
要运用它
Today so many of you have gathered here.
今天 很多人聚集在这里
I had never seen so many in Delhi before.
我从未见过德里有这么多人
Therefore,today every one of you must decide in mind
所以 请你们今天决定
that we will not accept any dishonest person at all.And the rakshasas too incarnate at this time due to these reasons.
不要相信不诚实的人 魔鬼在这里出生
Doesn't it go to show that we too have certain weaknesses within.
是因为我们内在有某些东西
That 's why  they believe that the weaknesses within us,
令它们以为我们会相信他们
Indians should never accept them.
印度人永远也不会相信
Besides the persons who have received their Realization , should never ever accept them.
那些已得自觉的灵也同样不会相信
There is a bad reputation about our country everywhere.
这是对我们国家的一种诽谤
But this is not true.
不是真的
There are several persons in India who are honest – in great number.
很多印度人 很多很多都很诚实
Nevertheless, it is not true
这种中伤不是真的
but I have seen it Myself that
我见过有人为土地战争
they will quarrel amongst each other saying,“This land is mine and that land is yours.”
这土地是我们的 那土地是你们的
Well whatever is yours is 'Swaraj'.
你们拥有的是swaraja
It is the 'rajya' (kingdom) of the 'swa' (Self).
自己的王国 我们自己的领域
Swaraj can only happen
当你变成真正swatantra
when you really become 'swatantra' in the true sense.
你拥有自己的王国
There is no need to be afraid of anyone. There is no need to tell anything to anyone.
不需要害怕任何人 不需要告诉任何人
I am astonished to see so many people.
我很惊讶的看到那么多人
I had never seen so many people in My life.
我从未在德里见过这么多人
So, I have only one request to you and that is today,
我唯一在这吉祥的日子要求你们的是
decide that we shall never commit dishonesty even if we have to die.
你们要作决定
secondly,if there is any dishonest, then collectively take care of him.
不要不诚实
By the way I told you all these things. But it seems the government is not able to do anything.
就算因此而死
In the  last 10 years our country deteriorated a lot .
我们的国家在过去十年已经开始衰落
You all are  Sahaja Yogis and  so many in numbers. Who are you all afraid of?
你们有这么多霎哈嘉瑜伽士
What is the reason to fear?
还害怕什么 有什么需要害怕
God is there behind everyone, to support.
上天支持每一个人
Just see for yourself, as soon as the Sufis realized
当苏非派知道上天与他们同在
they got rid of all those unwanted things that were around them
他们放弃世俗所有不要的东西
– not all, but a few of the sufis.
不是全部苏非派 只是少数这样做
That is what  you all should do.
你们也要这样做
In My opinion, the only message for today is that
今天的信息是你永远不能是贼
now  neither you are a cheat yourself, nor will help any cheat.
也不要支持任何贼
I have been reading in the papers that
我看到人们越来越为各种不同的原因争吵
there are differences over several other issues.
为种性(阶级)和宗教争吵
Well, are your efforts for protecting the country or for drowning ?
你来这里是要拯救国家 还是要被淹死
You have a great responsibility on you.
你肩负重大的责任
You are born in the Kali Yuga.
你在斗争期(kaliyuga)出生
That is why this Kali Yuga is to be transformed
斗争期必须改变
and you are all realized in the thousands.
这就是为什么那么多人得到自觉
Nowhere else have so many people been realized on Earth.
很多人在世界其他地方仍未得到自觉
That is why time and again I shall be repeating to you
这就是我为什么一次又一次请求你们
to stand on truth. I am with you.
站在真理之上 我会与你一起
And God is also with you.
神也与你一起
I was never worried about money.
请你们坚定的决定 不要容许偷窃 盗窃
that we shall not allow any offences like cheating or stealing to happen.
若发现任何不当的行为
Wherever we come to know of it, we will fight it out there.
都要对抗
I do not know what the people achieve by drinking alcohol or doing what?
但人们却像喝醉或其他
But in this light what do you receive? It is 'Courage'!
藉由这光 他们成就了些什么
so fight with courage!
勇气 勇敢的抗争
Whatever are wrong with this country should be removed.
无论什么是错的 必须从这国家移走
It has earned a very bad reputation.
我们的名声已经很败坏
There are many more issues,
仍有很多其他问题
but the most important one is that when there is no honesty at all,
但最重要的是若没有诚实
how is God going to help you?
神可以怎样帮助你
To earn money is not the help from God, but to be established in dharma is.
赚取金钱对神没有用的 但得到你的宗教却很有用 你必须成就它
There aren’t as many Sahaja Yogis anywhere else as you find here.
这个世界并没有太多霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Further,Sahaja Yogis never involve themselves doing such activities also.
霎哈嘉瑜伽士不会有这种行为
But I am telling you all this because
我告诉你这些是因为这里的气氛很坏
Over and above we have earned such a bad name all over.
我们每一处都有这种污名
You have everything with you - food to eat and drink, clothes to wear.
你有食物吃 有衣服穿
What else do you need?
还需要什么
You may enjoy movies, you enjoy that, you do have that much money.
你看电影 你的确拥有很多钱
But first of all, the obsession for the money should be got rid of.
但这种对金钱的沉迷却必须摆脱
I have full faith in you that you will listen to My today's lecture carefully.
我希望你们听我的话
And let us take an oath today
我们必须立誓
that we shall not commit dishonesty at all, also will oppose them who commits.
不会不诚实 只会反对不诚实的人
The most important message that is to be understood
要明白今天我们国家最需要的是诚实
Nothing is more important than that. Your Mother stands for honesty.
没有比诚实更重要 诚实是你的母亲
So what if you have only one shirt instead of ten?
你在一处有十件衬衣的地方 拥有一件衬衣又如何
Likewise convince these things to women also.
把同样的事告诉女士
It will work out.... It will happen.
它会发生 它必会发生
Today’s speech is a little bit different. It is unique...
今天的讲话有点不同 很独特
and you all have liked it. It was very kind of you.
你们都喜欢令我感到很亲切
Well then, thank you.
感谢大家